Cameron Leach

949.422.4800 | cameron.leach@gmail.com

Profile

Accomplished manager with over 10 years of software engineering experience and a proven track record of leading smoothly executed projects. A people-first leader of multiple engineering teams whose goal is to develop talent and make teams better by establishing a collaborative culture focused on detailed and quality execution in order to deliver the best products and results.

Experience

Disney Consumer Products and Interactive Media

Glendale, CA

Senior Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2017-Present

- Technical lead of the web platform engineering team, responsible for the architecture and development of over 50 systems and tools, including content, data and asset management systems that support numerous web and mobile app experiences across the Disney portfolio
- Oversees multiple functional engineering and product development teams, from reliability
 engineering and devops teams focused on uptime, performance and security, to the platform UX
 team with an emphasis on usability and design
- Led large-scale initiative as the primary technical and project leader to move Disney Interactive's
 main web platform to Google Cloud, featuring more than 30 major systems that support over
 800 guest-facing sites, including Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and
 starwars.com, resulting in multi-million dollar cost savings in system operations year over year
- Collaborates with platform leadership on developing strategy and roadmaps for project teams, involving both full-time and contingent workforce resources, that meet the needs of the organization within budget and on time
- Developed a team-wide knowledge share presentation series as a way to enhance engineering skills and knowledge while building a sense of community through informative presentations in a casual environment

Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2014-Dec 2016

- Led product and engineering for backend content management and data platform, which powers Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com
- Primary technical partner to product solutions team, providing technical guidance and custombuilt solutions to meet the needs of multiple stakeholders and global content production teams
- Managed revision of recommendation engine for Disney video portal that suggests related content through machine learning using Hadoop

Senior Software Engineer - Staff Software Engineer

May 2011-Dec 2013

- Architected and built an entirely new search platform for the major relaunch of disney.com using open-source software and frameworks like Apache Solr and Spring
- Optimized primary search algorithm leading to an increase in direct affiliate revenue from search on disney.com over 500% year over year
- Migrated several legacy disney.com sites and portals onto search platform, including Disney Channel, Disney XD and Walt Disney Company corporate sites
- Led front end and search engineering teams responsible for newly relaunched disney.com along with several internationalized companion sites in Latin America and Europe
- Worked on a fast-paced agile Labs team whose purpose was to innovate on experimental features, many of which became the foundation for the new disney.com

CityGrid Media/Citysearch

West Hollywood, CA

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2008-Apr 2011

- Led team of engineers in deployment of new search functionality during major site redesign with algorithm improvements leading to increases in conversions and revenue of over \$500k per year
- Architected and scaled multiple clusters of Apache Solr-based indexes containing more than
 18 million unique business listings performing advanced geo-spatial local searches
- Responsible for development and deployment of CityGrid public content APIs serving localized business listing profiles, search, deals and user reviews used by more than 100 partners
- Principal engineer on cross-functional scrum team responsible for building RESTful web applications for submission of user generated content including images, reviews and tweets
- Built server-side component of auto complete/predictive text functionality using Apache Lucene with index containing over 3 million search terms localized to specific geographic regions

Warner Bros. Advanced Digital Services

Burbank, CA

Associate Application Engineer

May 2006-Apr 2008

- Led development of online video distribution applications for both client and server utilizing
 Java technologies and Windows DRM to generate cost savings of over \$1 million for studio
- Involved in development of several consumer facing Java applications including flagship Warner Bros. web portal, CRM application, and content management systems

Education

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering and Computer Science

December 2005

- · Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- · USC Presidential Scholar
- USC SCion Scholar

Skills

Java (EE, SE) Ruby on Rails Apache Tomcat

Ruby Sinatra

XML

Google Cloud Platform MongoDB HTML
Google App Engine SQL JavaScript

Google Container Engine Apache Solr CSS

Lucene

Docker Mac OS X
Kubernetes Maven Unix/Linux

Helm Web Services/APIs

REST Agile Methodologies

Spring Framework Scrum

Hibernate Continuous Integration Kanban